Hi, my name is Dan Schmidt from the Chinese Martial Arts Center.
And today, we're going to be showing you the proper way to perform the Jump Outside Crescent Kick.
Okay, in this kick, there's a variety of steps that have a circular action.
Okay, so starting from a standing position, okay, your first step, you're going to go slightly outward towards the corner.
So you're going to step here, so one, then step as if you're turning; two, with your toes outward.
This is where you're going to be jumping.
So your knee comes up as you spin around, both hands go out, Outside Crescent Kick.
Okay.
So performed at full speed, it looks like this.
So he runs, step, jump and kick.
Okay.
So as soon as you take the second step, you have to whip your body around and jump up at the same time, to get the proper momentum of the spin.
So again, so you step out, round, jump, kick.
Okay, a few common errors, okay, is if you don't step out to the corner enough, you're not going to get the proper speed to turn around.
So you don't want to take two steps forward and then try to jump up and turn, it doesn't work.
So, you have to build up that speed by step out, turn the foot, you see and your body is turning up and then the kick.
Okay.
So once again.
So step, jump, kick.
That's the proper way to perform the Jump Outside Crescent Kick.